(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T22:09:14.432197",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To All Attendees
どアニメ宣言
Direct Anime Declaration!
アニメにハマって 歌いたくなっちゃった
I got hooked on anime, and now I just want to sing!
推しのシーン見ながらカラオケ歌えるなんて…
Being able to sing karaoke while watching my favorite scene...
尊すぎてツラいっ！
It's so precious, it hurts!
歌いたいアニメ・ゲームソング見つけよう！
Let's find the anime and game songs you want to sing!
JOYSOUND！
JOYSOUND!
全国のアミューズメント施設でGETしてね♪
Get them at amusement facilities nationwide!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ご来場のお客様へ
Notice to Visitors
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
【Attention】 演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
[Attention] Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is OK.
本日は星街すいせい Live「SuperNova REBOOT」にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova REBOOT" today.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure everyone enjoys the live show until the end, here are a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, audio recording, and video recording during the show are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
Smoking is strictly prohibited inside the venue. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If you feel unwell at any point, please do not push yourself and inform nearby staff.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、大きく飛び跳ねる、ステージにものを投げ込むなど、
Mosh pits, diving, jumping excessively, or throwing objects onto the stage,
他のみんなの迷惑になったり公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
as well as any other behavior that bothers others or disrupts the show, are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってください。
Please follow the rules and enjoy the show!
みんな今日持ってきてくれてるうちわもね、高く掲げすぎないように気をつけてくださいね。
Also, if you brought fan fans today, please be careful not to hold them up too high.
ありがとう！後ろの人見えなくなっちゃうからね。
Thank you! Otherwise the people behind you won't be able to see.
また本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
Additionally, cameras for video streaming and photography will be present, so audience members may be captured.
映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please be aware that footage and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
はい！
Alright!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは、ハッシュタグ「#駆け巡る星街...さい」です！
Also, the hashtag for this live is #駆け巡る星街さい!
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください！
Please use the hashtag and post a lot to build excitement!
いっぱい見たよ、タグ。ありがとうね、いっぱい投稿してくれて！
I've seen so many posts with the tag! Thank you for posting so much!
それでは！
Now then!
開演までもう少しです！
It's almost time for the show to start!
みんなで一緒に盛り上がりましょう！
Let's all get hyped together!
星街すいせいでした！
This was Hoshimachi Suisei!
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
革命の、その先へ。
Beyond the revolution.
Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova: REBOOT"
K-Arena!
盛り上がる準備できてますかー！
Are you ready to get hyped?!
さて、すいちゃんはここだよー！
Now then, Sui-chan is right here!
見えますかー？ここだよー！
Can you see me? I'm over here!
見つけて見つけて！すいちゃんここだよー！
Find me, find me! Sui-chan is right here!
みんながよく見えるー！
I can see all of you so clearly!
みんなこっちこっちー！
Everyone, over here, over here!
みんなの持ってるやつ見せてくださーい！
Show me what you're holding!
いいねー、みんなの顔よく見えるよー！
Nice! I can see your faces so well!
ぬいぐるみもたくさん、ありがとー！
Thanks for bringing so many plushies!
つまんないデイ もう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life where you're just wishing for miracles
Watch me do...
呪術 秘中 トリック無しのマジック
Secret incantations, magic with no tricks
I wanna be free! だってまだふりだし
I wanna be free! Because I'm still at square one
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙まで
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
12時まで
Until 12 o'clock,
夜更かしは
staying up late
音を立てて 夜を急かす
makes noise and rushes the night,
魔法の馬車
like a magical carriage.
人生は 一瞬にして
Life is a spell
溶ける魔法 それならば
that breaks in an instant; if so,
駆け抜けてわっほい ダーリン
run through it with a 'wah-hoi', darling!
お邪魔なお邪魔虫乗せて Drive me
Carrying annoying pests, Drive me
あたしは大変身 Make up
I'm making a big transformation, Make up
わがままのままで Money Money
Staying selfish, Money Money
きらめきに チュッチュッ
Blow a kiss to the sparkle, chu chu
騒ぐの忘れて Dancing
Forget about causing a fuss, Dancing
ありがとー！
Thank you!
みなみなご唱和あれ！
Everyone, chant along!
こんがら could break でもしょうがないから Shhh て踊っちゃう Night
It's all tangled and could break, but it can't be helped, so Shhh, dance the night away!
今夜に明日はないならば 自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう
If there's no tomorrow for tonight, whoever dances freely wins!
見えてるよー！
I can see you!
Z-Z-Z-Z-Z Slider Ho
どんな問題も会話ひとつ
Any problem takes just one conversation
庇心も正解も間違いも
Kindness, right answers, and mistakes
愛す本当のあたしノリノリさ
Loving the real me, I'm grooving!
あらら世界は限界の気配がして
Oh my, the world seems to be at its limit,
ただただ安心じゃ心配？
is just peace of mind worrying?
じゃあ今すぐ Jumping Jumping Now!
Then right now, Jumping Jumping Now!
チクチクバンバン チュチュチュバンバン 言いだくだくの期待大だ
Chiku-chiku bang-bang, chu-chu-chu bang-bang, expectations are high for obedience
ギリギリ破格のキミ たった今
You, barely bargain-priced, right now,
破産してしまおうか！
shall we go completely broke?
インパスじゃちっとも足りないわ
Impasse isn't enough at all
ついに導き出したキミにアンサー
The answer I finally derived for you
灰になるまで踊ってよ
Dance until you turn to ash!
最高！
Awesome!
見えてるよ見えてるよー！
I see you, I see you!
お邪魔なお邪魔虫乗せて Drive me
Carrying annoying pests, Drive me
あたしは大変身 Make up
I'm making a big transformation, Make up
わがままのままで Money Money
Staying selfish, Money Money
きらめきに チュッチュッ
Blow a kiss to the sparkle, chu chu
騒ぐの忘れて Dancing
Forget about causing a fuss, Dancing
さよなら Good bye, Red, Yellow, Green
Goodbye, Good bye, Red, Yellow, Green
きっと関心さ クラブ ワーディーズ
Surely interested, Club Worldies
みなみなご唱和あれ！
Everyone, chant along!
こんがら could break でもしょうがないから Shhh て踊っちゃう Night
It's all tangled and could break, but it can't be helped, so Shhh, dance the night away!
今夜に明日はないならば 自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう
If there's no tomorrow for tonight, whoever dances freely wins!
遠くて 近くて すぐそばにいるのに
Far away, yet close, even though I'm right beside you,
僕がどれくらい 知られているのだろう
I wonder how much I am known to you.
眺める空 見つめるときに 焦がれて流れる
When I gaze at the sky I look up at, longing flows...
消えないでよ
Don't disappear.
祈るたび 輝いて
Shining every time I pray,
運命なのか 幻なのか
is it destiny, or is it an illusion?
旋律が心の輪に咲く
A melody blooms in the ring of my heart.
送別の歌声を脱ぎ捨てたい
I want to strip away this song of farewell,
自由をあなたと抱きしめたい
I want to embrace freedom with you.
同じ夢の中 目覚めたのなら
If we woke up inside the same dream,
掴んだ不安も眠るのに
even the anxiety we grabbed onto would sleep.
ここには僕らしくいられない
Here, I cannot be myself.
残した窓の外には言葉があり
Outside the window I left behind, there are words,
秘めた声 静かに響き渡っていく
hidden voices quietly echoing across.
あなたの面影へと帰りたい
I want to return to your memory.
この声は届いてる？
Is this voice reaching you?
心はここにある
My heart is right here.
どんな未来へ繋がっていくんだろう
What kind of future are we connecting to?
伏し目がちな君のサインと
With your downcast eyes and sign,
にじむ向こうから いつまでそこに
from beyond the blur, how long will you stay there...
祈るたび 包まれて
Enfolded every time I pray,
哀憐なのか 孤独なのか
is it pity, or is it solitude?
旋律が心の輪に咲く
A melody blooms in the ring of my heart.
誰にも言えずにみつめるだけ
Unable to tell anyone, just gazing...
送別の歌声を脱ぎ捨てたい
I want to strip away this song of farewell,
自由をあなたと抱きしめたい
I want to embrace freedom with you.
同じ夢の中 目覚めたのなら
If we woke up inside the same dream...
だって僕は僕で眠るのに
Even though I sleep as myself,
ここには僕だと言い換えられない
I can't rephrase who I am here.
覗いた窓のストーリーは深まり
The story seen through the window deepens,
秘めた声 滴に響き渡っていく
and hidden voices ripple across like droplets.
あなたの発想へと変えていきたい
I want to transform into your way of thinking.
配信のみなさんもっかい聴かせてください！
Everyone on the stream, let me hear you once more!
引き切った太陽に向かわされて
Forced to face the setting sun,
ずっと縛り付けられている街の上
forever bound above the city.
あぁ 掴まったメッセージが流れ出して
Ah, trapped messages start to flow,
落ちて 濁った街の底へ歌っていく
falling to the depths of the murky city, as I sing.
きっと誰かもただ一人で
Surely someone else is all alone,
愚痴をつぶやきながら泣いているんだ
muttering complaints while crying.
嫌じゃない
I don't hate it,
愛してる
I love it,
大嫌い
I hate it,
大好き
I love it so,
ただ重い辛いの
it's just heavy and painful.
思いが合わさる
My feelings come together,
試行錯誤して
through trial and error,
咲いていく この感情が
these emotions begin to bloom.
音の中で初めて惹かれ合うんだね
They attract each other for the first time within sound,
歌の中で初めて響き出すんだね
and begin to echo for the first time within song.
冷め切った体温と
With completely chilled body heat,
並んだ無表情に
and standing in line expressionlessly,
臆病になっていた街の上
I had grown fearful above the city.
叶わない重力と
Against an unbeatable gravity,
地上までの超重力
and supergravity drawing down to earth,
名前もないものを見つけられている
even something nameless is being discovered.
なんてどこかで吐いた言い訳が
Is just an excuse I blurted out somewhere,
声を奪ったまま
stealing my voice away,
呪いみたいになっているんだ 今更
turning into a curse after all this time.
「解ってよ」
"Understand me!"
信じて
Believe me!
「嘘つき」
"Liar!"
嫌になるくらいの
So much that it sickens me,
重さを失う
losing all weight,
今日も振り回されていく重力
being thrown around by gravity again today.
あぁ 飛び上がる準備をしている
Ah, preparing to jump high!
何もかも半端で
Everything is half-baked,
犯して
making mistakes,
沈んでいく
sinking down.
人違い
Mistaken identity?
信じたい
I want to believe,
そうだよ
that's right,
that's right.
嫌じゃない
I don't hate it,
好きじゃない
I don't love it,
全部ただ一つだ
it's all just one thing.
解りたい
I want to understand,
どうしたい？
what do I want to do?
「聞かせて」
"Let me hear it!"
伝えたい
I want to tell you!
愛してる
I love it,
大嫌い
I hate it,
大好き
I love it so,
ただ重い辛いの
it's just heavy and painful.
重さの最後まで
Until the very end of weight,
今日もまた叫んでる
I'm screaming again today,
この感情が
this emotion...
音の中で初めて惹かれ合うまで
...until we attract each other within sound for the first time,
あなたのその胸で響き出すまで
...until it begins to echo in your heart!
愛してる
I love it,
大嫌い
I hate it,
嘘だよ
that's a lie,
「大好き」
"I love it so!"
改めましてー！
Once again, hello everyone!
盛り上がってますねー！
You guys are pumped up!
ということで、星街すいせいライブ SUPERNOVA ReLIVE と、いよいよ始まりましたー！
So, Hoshimachi Suisei's live 'SUPERNOVA ReLIVE' has finally begun!
みなさん、びっくりしたんじゃないですか？
Everyone, were you surprised?
冒頭ね
At the beginning,
ねえ
Hey.
一瞬 どこにいるかわからなかったんじゃないかな？
For a second, you couldn't tell where I was, could you?
わからなかったね！
You couldn't tell, right!
あれ？出てこない、出てこないぞ？あれ？って思ったかな？
You were probably thinking, "Huh? She's not coming out! Huh?"
あの端っこのね、あそこらへんの人はね
People over near the edge around there...
「うわあー！」ってなったことと思いますけれども
I bet you went, "Waaaaah!"
さあ、ありがとう！
Now then... thank you!
まずは、自己紹介からね、行きたいと思いますよ！
First off, let me start with my introduction!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
A rough diamond of a star that appeared like a comet! I'm the virtual idol, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいーちゃんはー？
Sui-chan is...?
いやー
Wow...
元気だね、君たち、今日も！
You guys are so full of energy today too!
いやー
Wow...
え、でもさ、まだ行けるんじゃない？
Wait, but... you can still go harder, right?
じゃあ行くよ！
Alright, here we go!
すいーちゃんはー？
Sui-chan is...?
できるやないかー！
You CAN do it after all!
さてさて、今回のライブはですね
Now then, for today's live...
去年行いました武道館公演の再現として
as a restaging of last year's Budokan concert,
あのセットリストとかはね、結構似てるんですけど
the setlist and everything is pretty similar,
2曲目がもう既にね、前回と違いましたね？
but the second song was already different from last time, right?
ね？
Right?
あ、じゃあ結構、なんか変わってたりするのかなー？
Oh, so maybe quite a bit has changed?
とか言って全然変わってなかったり
Or maybe it hasn't changed at all despite saying that!
まあただ、ひとつ言えるのは
Well, the one thing I can say is...
このKアリーナという会場でやりたかった演出とか
stage effects I wanted to do here at K-Arena...
もう、レーザーバチバチとかもう演出がもう盛り盛りになってるんで
like intense lasers and super upgraded production elements...
めっちゃめちゃグレードアップしてるんで！
It's been upgraded so much!
で、私自身もたくさん練習してきましたんで！
And I've been practicing a lot myself too!
ダンスとかね！
Like dancing!
ちょっと頑張ってきたんでね！
I worked hard on it!
そういう、去年からパワーアップした姿をお見せできればなと思って
I wanted to show you all how much I've powered up since last year,
はい、このライブとなっております！
so that's what this live is all about!
さて、今回もですね
Now then, today as well...
えー、いつもの通りバンドさんを引き連れております！バンドさーん！
as always, I'm joined by the live band! Band members!
そして、そして！
And, and!
ちょっ、リハのね、動画とかをショートで投稿させてもらってるんですけど
I've been posting rehearsal videos on Shorts, but...
気づいた人いるよね？！
Some of you noticed, right?!
今回はストリングスさんがいらっしゃいまーす！ストリングスさーん！
This time, we have a strings section! Strings team!
イエーイ！もう格好いいんだから、ストリングス入るだけでね！
Yay! It sounds so cool just having strings added!
ストリングスって何か知ってる？あれだよ、あの...
Do you know what strings are? It's, you know...
ヴァイオリン、ウィーンウィーンウィーンってやるやつね！
Violins, the ones that go "wheen wheen wheen"!
いや、今日しか聞けないライブアレンジをね
Yeah, live arrangements you can only hear today...
バンドさんがたくさん、たくさん作ってくださいましたので！
the band created so, so many of them for us!
もうしょっぱなからビビデバのね、ストリングスが入ったバージョンがかっこよすぎて、アゲアゲになっちゃいましたね！
Right from the start, the strings version of Bibbidiba was so cool that I got super hyped!
めっちゃ良かったー！
It was so good!
さあ、そして、そして
Now then, and also...
残念ながらここに来られなかった星詠みたちがいます
there are Hoshiyomi who unfortunately couldn't be here in person.
ここに...
Right here...
ここに来られなかった星詠みたち...
The Hoshiyomi who couldn't make it here...
画面の向こうの君たち！
You guys on the other side of the screen!
「行きたかったよー！」って言ってるの、お前きっとるやないかー！
"I wanted to go!" ...Wait, I can hear you saying that!
ちょっとなんかね、ここらへんになんか...
I feel like right around here...
「ここにいるぞー！あ、見... 見てるよー！あ！」
"I'm right here! Ah, I'm... I'm watching! Ah!"
「イエーイ！俺はここにいるぞー！」
"Yay! I'm right here!"
「あ、行きたかった... あ、吊るされてます... 号泣...」
"Ah, I wanted to go... Ah, I'm suspended... Crying out loud..."
悲しいな...「ニューヨークからこんにちは！」あ、ニューヨークからこんにちはー！
How sad... "Hello from New York!" Ah, hello from New York!
え、気になるよ！
Wait, now I'm curious!
海外星詠みの皆さん！
Overseas Hoshiyomi!
す、すごい...
Wo-Wow...
え、海外星詠みではない皆さん！
And those of you who aren't overseas Hoshiyomi!
素晴らしい！もうどっちも素晴らしいですね！
Wonderful! You're both wonderful!
はい、ということで、配信の方もですね、たくさんファンサしますので
Alright, so I'll be doing plenty of fan service for the stream viewers too,
寂しくさせませんからね！絶対最初から最後まで全部見てくださいね！はい、バチコン！
so I won't let you feel lonely! Make sure to watch from beginning to end! Bam!
ではでは、ライブの感想はハッシュタグ #駆け巡る星街再 でたくさんポストしてください！
Now then, please post lots of your thoughts about the live using the hashtag #駆け巡る星街再 !
ポスト？
Post...?
ツイートだよなあ？！
It's tweet, isn't it?!
ツイートだなあ！まったく、台本はいつまでもポストって書いてあるんだから... おかしいなあ...
It's tweet! Seriously, the script always has "post" written on it... How strange...
さて、YouTube、TikTokでご覧の...
Now, for those watching on YouTube or TikTok...
タダで見ているあなたたち
All of you watching for free,
3曲までよ
it's only up to three songs!
タダで見れるのは
That you get to watch for free...
ありがとう 代わりにね いてくれて ありがとう
Thank you, for being here instead. Thank you.
さあ まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは
Now then, everyone who wants to keep partying with us,
概要欄から！
check the description!
下なのかな？上なのかな？下かな？
Is it below? Or above? Below, maybe?
概要欄から配信サイトへ レッツゴー！
From the description box, let's go to the streaming site!
いいですか？皆さん
Are you ready, everyone?
盛り上がる準備出来てますか？次行っちゃっていいんですか？
Are you ready to get hyped? Can we move on to the next song?
リブートした SUPERNOVA
The rebooted SUPERNOVA,
全身で浴びてください！
soak it all in with your whole body!